Let's discuss managed project knowledge
ITTOs now.
Page 98 in your PINBOC.
All right, so here we're documenting.
So those OPAs keep coming in, inputs.
Well, we are also supposed to contribute
to project knowledge.
So let's cover our ITTOs.
So our inputs are a project management
plan.
It's given.
It's coming in.
Project documents,
you will see the Lessons
Learned Register, but this is the process.
I'm going right over here to the outputs.
This is the actual process that will
create our Lessons Learned Register.
We will be documenting what's going well,
what's not going well.
We won't do this just once, so that's why
later Lessons Learned Register will come
into a lot of our processes will update it
on the way out again a register is
something we hold in our hot little hands
with all the details the deliverables will
come in also those EEFs and OPAs so
remember four main topics will be
organizational culture structure and
governance the project management
information system PMIS huge all our
project information is coming in and out
of there organizational resources,
people, material, equipment, supplies,
facilities, and government
and industry standards,
laws, regulations we're
going to have to follow.
Our OPAs, again, we follow the policies,
processes, procedures, guidelines,
methods on our project.
PMO is telling us what to
do, how to do our projects,
and huge, we'll pull from
that knowledge repository.
Those are your OPAs, historical
information, lessons learn, repositories,
what's happened in previous, similar
recently completed project files.
We use those.
All right, so tools and techniques,
what we'll do to manage project knowledge?
We'll use expert judgment again.
Then we have knowledge management.
And to make it very clear, I would like
you to go to your PIMBOC over on page 102.
two and you'll see on the second line
tacit knowledge tacit knowledge so here
these are usually this is usually
knowledge not readily codified these are
feelings beliefs and we want to try to
document them so we have to create an
atmosphere of trust so that people will
actually open up for example, we've done
similar projects, a few similar projects
in the past.
We keep getting to a point where we start
getting kicked back from the stakeholders.
We need this tacit knowledge.
We need to document.
Well, what are you feeling?
What is making you feel uncomfortable
right now?
Okay.
So that is knowledge management.
Then over on the next page, we have
information management.
And I believe, yep, it's on the second
line again like in the middle explicit
knowledge so this is usually readily
codified we can document we can create a
document a diagram so that's information
management and again because we will get
this knowledge from our team members they
are stakeholders and other stakeholders we
use those interpersonal
team skills you'll see
active listening nodding,
repeating back will be big.
All right, we'll facilitate the meetings.
We will use leadership, in part vision,
networking, and using political awareness.
What do we create when we manage project
knowledge?
Again, this is very important,
our lessons learned register.
We will document what's going well,
what's not going well.
We'll update any plans that might be
affected and contribute to update the OPAs.